Finding Aid for Jack Kevorkian papers, 1911-2014
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Research and Practice
  - Audio recordings
    - I need Dr. Jack by Josh Weinstein, 1996, digitized audio cassette
      - [Side 1 of 2], [2014106-SR-7-1]; (Unexpected content; Tape of unknown speaker discussing high medical costs, cardiomiopathy and colloidal minerals.)
      - [Side 2 of 2], [2014106-SR-7-2]; (Unexpected content; Tape of unknown speaker discussing high medical costs, cardiomiopathy and colloidal minerals.)
    - Kevin Joyce radio show, 1989 October 27, digitized audio cassette
      - [Side 1 of 2], [2014106-SR-8-1]; (WJR radio; Jack Kevorkian interviewed on the Kevin Joyce radio show discussing his assistant suicide methods. Callers also voice their opinions.)
      - [Side 2 of 2], [2014106-SR-8-2]; (WJR radio; Jack Kevorkian interviewed on the Kevin Joyce radio show discussing his assistant suicide methods. Callers also voice their opinions.)
    - Kevorkian and Fieger on WJR 760AM, 1993 September 02, digitized audio cassette
      - [Side 1 of 2], [2014106-SR-9-1]; (Kevin Joyce show discussing Michigan politics, no mention of Kevorkian.)
      - [Side 2 of 2], [2014106-SR-9-2]; (Distortion throughout. Conservative talk show discussing assisted suicide and other topics.)
    - Kevorkian Café, undated, undated, digitized audio cassette
      - [Side 1 of 1], [2014106-SR-10-1]; (Tape is very distorted. Songs about assisted suicide.)
    - Kevorkian and Fieger on WJR 760AM, 1993 September 02, Audio Cassette
      - [Side 1 of 2], [2014106-SR-9-1]; (Kevin Joyce show discussing Michigan politics, no mention of Kevorkian.)
      - [Side 2 of 2], [2014106-SR-9-2]; (Distortion throughout. Conservative talk show discussing assisted suicide and other topics.)
    - Larry King and Mary Ruwart, 1993 February - March, digitized audio cassette
      - [Side 1 of 2], [2014106-SR-11-1]; (Interview with a family member of a recent recipient of Dr. Kevorkian's services. At 18:00 recording of John Engler discussing a law making assisted suicide illegal and news recordings of Mary Ruwart and potential legal challenges to Dr. Kevorkian.)
      - [Side 2 of 2], [2014106-SR-11-2]; (Unexpected content: Speaker discussing the universe, biological cycles, and enhancing sensory perception.)
    - The Mercy Machine, 1990, digitized audio cassette
      - [Side 1 of 1], [2014106-SR-14-1]; (Dr. Kevorkian on a radio program discussing his experiences with his assisted suicide machine and patients he has worked with.)
    - McCullough Show, 1988 August 09, digitized audio cassette
      - [Side 1 of 2], [2014106-SR-15-1]; (Jack Kevorkian discussing harvesting of organs from death row inmates.)
      - [Side 2 of 2], [2014106-SR-15-2]; (Jack Kevorkian discussing harvesting of organs from death row inmates.)
    - Mike Scott Show, 1992 July 22, digitized audio cassette
      - [Side 1 of 2], [2014106-SR-16-1]; (Radio program debating the moral ethics of assisted suicide on WXYT.)
      - [Side 2 of 2], [2014106-SR-16-2]; (Radio program debating the moral ethics of assisted suicide on WXYT.)
    - Jack Kevorkian interview on organ donation, 1993 August 01, digitized audio cassette
      - [Side 1 of 1], [2014106-SR-17-1]; (Jack Kevorkian on a radio program discussing the ethics of harvesting organs from death row inmates.)
    - Right to Die (Geoffrey Fieger), 1993 June 27, digitized audio cassette
      - [Side 1 of 2], [2014106-SR-25-1]; (Several doctors debate Dr. Kevorkian's lawyer Geoffrey Fieger and the ethics of assisted suicide on Sunday Rounds radio program.)
      - [Side 2 of 2], [2014106-SR-25-2]; (Several doctors debate Dr. Kevorkian's lawyer Geoffrey Fieger and the ethics of assisted suicide on Sunday Rounds radio program.)
    - SBS Armenian Radio interview, Melbourne, 1997 October 15, digitized audio cassette
      - [Side 1 of 2], [2014106-SR-26-1]; (Radio program in Armenian with Jack Kevorkian, features multiple content include talk and music.)
      - [Side 2 of 2], [2014106-SR-26-2]; (Radio program with Jack Kevorkian interviewed on SBS Armenian radio. Portions of this program are in Armenian.)
    - Testimonials by Healthcare Professionals, volume 2, 1996, digitized audio cassette
      - [Side 1 of 2], [2014106-SR-27-1]; (Several speakers testifying about their success with the Bios Life 2 and other products.)
      - [Side 2 of 2], [2014106-SR-27-2]; (Several speakers testifying about their success with the Bios Life 2 and other products.)
    - Victoria Jones Show, 1992 July 21, digitized audio cassette
      - [Side 1 of 2], [2014106-SR-28-1]; (Jack Kevorkian and his lawyer Geoffrey Fieger interviewed on the Victoria Jones Show following the verdict of Kevorkian not being gulity.)
      - [Side 2 of 2], [2014106-SR-28-2]; (Jack Kevorkian and his lawyer Geoffrey Fieger interviewed on the Victoria Jones Show following the verdict of Kevorkian not being gulity.)
    - Vocabulary, undated, digitized audio cassette
      - [Side 1 of 2], [2014106-SR-29-1]; (Jack Kevorkian reading from the dictionary.)
      - [Side 2 of 2], [2014106-SR-29-2]; (Jack Kevorkian reading from the dictionary.)
    - Vocabulary, undated, digitized audio cassette
      - [Side 1 of 2], [2014106-SR-30-1]; (Jack Kevorkian reading from the dictionary.)
      - [Side 2 of 2], [2014106-SR-30-2]; (Jack Kevorkian reading from the dictionary.)
    - Vocabulary and interview on KCBS (damaged tape), undated, digitized audio cassette
      - [Side 1 of 2], [2014106-SR-31-1]; (Jack Kevorkian reading from the dictionary.)
      - [Side 2 of 2], [2014106-SR-31-2]; (Jack Kevorkian reading from the dictionary, next portion is Jack Kevorkian interviewed on KCBS on assisted suicide. Distortion for about 10 seconds at 22:30.)
  - Miscellaneous items
    (business cards, photographs, etc. bl019113-bl019123)
- Morganroth & Morganroth
  The Morganroth & Morganroth series (1982-2013, 2.7 linear feet) contains records from attorney Mayer ("Mike") Morganroth's office. Material includes Morganroth's professional correspondence on various subjects related to Kevorkian's trials, photocopies and originals of Kevorkian's correspondence, and material related to Morganroth's personal relationship with Dr. Kevorkian. The series contains a sizable amount of Research Files, mostly material that was used by Morganroth for defense legal research, specifically, Kevorkian's notes and drafts relating to scientific and ethical issues. Some duplication between these materials and Kevorkian's research files and manuscript drafts (included in the Research and Practice series) is possible. The series also contains a small number of legal documents: Retainer Agreement between Geoffrey N. Fieger and Jack Kevorkian together with an Affidavit of Jack Kevorkian, M.D. in the Circuit Court for the County of Oakland (1990), a Motion to Dismiss in the Circuit Court for the County of Oakland (1996), an Order by the Circuit Court for the 6th Judicial Circuit Oakland Court (1999), and a Petition for Writ of Certiorari in the Supreme Court of the United States (2002). Of special interest is the script of HBO's You Don't Know Jack, annotated by Morganroth with corrections and suggestions. Morganroth's records also include inventories of Kevorkian's paintings and personal property left after Kevorkian's death as well as correspondence discussing auctioning Kevorkian's paintings.
  - Biographical and personal, Kevorkian (Box 5)
    (includes photograph)
  - "Black binder" (compilation of articles and other material about Kevorkian's trial), 1991-2005 (Box 5)
  - Congressional run, 2008 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence
    (see also Research and Practice series)
    - Undated (Box 5)
    - 1982-1998, 3 folders (Box 5)
    - October 27, 2003-December 5, 2005 (Box 5)
      (bound)
    - January 5, 2006-May 31, 2007 (Box 5)
    - 2000-2011 (Box 5)
      (scattered)
  - Court documents, 1990-2002 (Box 5)
  - Inventories, 2011-2013 (Box 6)
    (art and other items; includes photographs)
  - Manuscripts
    - GlimmerIQs (Box 6)
    - When the People Bubble POPs (Box 6)
    - You Don't Know Jack (Box 6)
  - Media, (collected articles) 2007-2009 (Box 6)
  - Nicol, Neal, 1998 undated (Box 6)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 7)
  - Research files, 6 folders (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
- Personal Interests
  The Personal Interests series (1960s-2008, 0.4 linear feet, oversize items, and digital files) includes collected materials about Armenia, posters and images of his art, and photos taken during his art exhibits and music practice.
  Also found here are 40 laminated 36" x 36" plastic placards with excerpts from the Constitution and statements attributed to Benjamin Franklin, Thomas Jefferson, Gore Vidal, Albert Einstein, and others. The placards were created by Kevorkian by hand and taken by him to Washington, D.C. As Ava Janus explained, "The point of these was supposed to be an introduction to the average American citizen as to the importance of the Ninth Amendment that few people really know anything about. [...] Uncle was trying to show that his enemies got away with putting him into prison because that Ninth Amendment wasn't being used or enforced, and that this could happen to anyone, not just him. Uncle felt that if he used profound sayings and statements from the great and/or famous people, alive or from the past, to illustrate his point, that everyone would understand and insist that the Ninth be more used." [Excerpt is from the accompanying note, submitted by Ava Janus, to the Bentley Historical Library.]
  - Armenia, 1960s-1990s (Box 8 A)
    (correspondence and collected materials, mostly in Armenian)
  - Art
    - "Amendment IX: Our Cornucopia of Rights," undated (Box 9)
      (stencil made for Kevorkian's last canvas)
    - Art exhibits (Box 8 A)
      - 1994-1999, 2008, 2 folders (Box 8 A)
      - Art work, 1994, 1999
        (photos and exhibition ads depicting Kevorkian's paintings. bl019124-bl019161)
  - Collected books (Box 8 A)
    (autographed and annotated)
  - Music
    - Audio recordings
      - Deathdub (Musical group?), 1993 March 27, digitized audio cassette
        - [Side 1 of 2], [2014106-SR-5-1]; (Noise collage and electro-acoustic music on the subject of assisted suicide.)
        - [Side 2 of 2], [2014106-SR-5-2]; (Song entitled "Jack Smith Says" acoustic noise music.)
      - JK mixes, undated (was CD)
      - Melodic Death by The Quest, 1993, digitized audio cassette
        - [Side 1 of 1], [2014106-SR-13-1]; (Metal song about assisted suicide.)
      - Organ music, 1995, Audio Cassette
        - [Side 1 of 2], [2014106-SR-18-1]; (Recital of Jack Kevorkian's organ music. First few minutes of recording is an introduction by Kevorkian.)
        - [Side 2 of 2], [2014106-SR-18-2]; (Recital of Jack Kevorkian's organ music performed by Kevorkian.)
      - Organ music, undated, digitized audio cassette
        - [Side 1 of 1], [2014106-SR-21-1]; (Recital of Jack Kevorkian's organ music performed by Kevorkian.)
      - Organ music, undated, digitized audio cassette
        - [Side 1 of 1], [2014106-SR-22-1]; (Recital of Jack Kevorkian's organ music performed by Kevorkian.)
      - Piano music, 1997, digitized audio cassette
        - [Side 1 of 2], [2014106-SR-23-1]; (These sound to be recordings played back on an electric piano or a computer.)
        - [Side 2 of 2], [2014106-SR-23-2]; (Background noise for the first minute. These sound to be recordings played back on an electric piano or a computer.)
      - Piano music, 1997, digitized audio cassette
        - [Side 1 of 2], [2014106-SR-24-1]; (These sound to be recordings played back on an electric piano or a computer.)
        - [Side 2 of 2], [2014106-SR-24-2]; (These sound to be recordings played back on an electric piano or a computer.)
      - The Semi-Suite, undated (CD)
      - A Very Still Life, 1997 (CD)
    - Compositions (list), correspondence, programs, 1966, 1995 undated (Box 8 A)
    - Photographs, 1990s (Box 8 A)
    - Poster of documentary Messiah, 1977 (Box 9)
    - Sheet music
      - Compositions for flute, 1997-1998 (Box 8 A)
      - Compositions for organ, 1981-1996 (Box 8 A)
      - Compositions for piano, 1997-1998 (Box 8 A)
      - Compositions for string instruments, 1997-1998 (Box 8 A)
      - Compositions for tuba and cello, 1997 (Box 8 A)
  - 40 laminated placards, 36" x 36", undated (Object 3)
- Medicide files
  The Medicide Files series (1986-2005, 0.6 linear feet and digital files) contains materials related to the terminally ill people and their families who were assisted by Kevorkian. The material contains Medicide subject files (including blank forms developed by Kevorkian for Medicide "patient" files), proposals, and other materials. Medicide files include correspondence, medical histories, photographs, and digitized video and audio recordings of consultations. Also present are photographs depicting gathering signatures under petitions and of the Medicide families.
  - Subject files
    - Forms, undated (Box 8 A)
    - Physicians for Mercy, 1995 1997 (Box 8 A)
    - Proposal for the State of Ohio Department of Rehabilitation and Correction (Box 8 A)
    - Research, 1986-2005 (Box 8 A)
  - File no. 1
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
      [Duplication Prohibited]
  - File no. 2
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
    - Consultations, 1992 November 22 and 23, [2014106-18]; digitized VHS videotape; 00:53:49
  - File no. 3
    - Consultation, 1994 March 26, [2014106-36]; digitized VHS videotape; 00:14:08
  - File no. 4 (Box 8)
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
  - File no. 5
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
  - File no. 6
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
  - File no. 7
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
    - Consultations, 1995 April 20 and May 7, [2014106-19]; digitized VHS videotape; 00:26:56
  - File no. 8
    - Consultation, 1993 October 12, [2014106-39]; digitized VHS videotape; 00:21:41
  - File no. 9
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
    - Consultations, 1993 January 20 and February 11, [2014106-20]; digitized VHS videotape; 01:13:42
  - File no. 10
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
    - Consultation, 1995 June 26, [2014106-21]; digitized VHS videotape; 00:09:31
  - File no. 11
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
    - Recording, 1992, digitized audio cassette
      - [Side 1 of 1], [2014106-SR-12-1]
  - File no. 12
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
    - Consultations, 1993 January 3 and February 8, [2014106-22]; digitized VHS videotape; 00:52:45
  - File no. 13
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
    - Consultation, 1993 February 17, [2014106-23]; digitized VHS videotape; 00:13:43
  - File no. 14
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
    - Consultation,1992 September 19, [2014106-26]; digitized VHS videotape; 00:34:52
    - Consultation, 1992 September 26, [2014106-24]; digitized VHS videotape; 00:21:07
  - File no. 15
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
  - File no. 16, 2014106-37
    - Consultation, 1998 July 30, [2014106-37]; digitized VHS Videotape; 00:23:28
  - File no. 17 (Box 8)
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
  - File no. 18
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
    - Consultations, 1992 September 5 and 19, [2014106-25]; digitized VHS Videotape; 01:31:25
    - Consultation, 1992 September 19, [2014106-40]; digitized VHS Videotape; 01:06:18
  - File no. 19
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
    - Consultation, 1995 May 12, [2014106-27]; digitized VHS videotape; 00:15:04
  - File no. 20
    - Consultation, 1995 July 18, [2014106-41]; digitized VHS videotape; 00:16:49
  - File no. 21
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
    - Consultation, 1992 December 19, [2014106-28]; digitized VHS videotape; 00:24:09
  - File no. 22
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
  - File no. 23
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
  - File no. 24
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
    - Consultation, 1993 September 8, [2014106-29]; digitized VHS videotape; 00:21:27
  - File no. 25
    - Consultation, 1993 February 10, [2014106-38]; digitized VHS videotape; 00:23:20
  - File no. 26
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
    - Consultation, 1993 February 17, [2014106-30]; digitized VHS videotape; 00:16:42
  - File no. 27
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
    - Consultations, 1992 May 9 and December 14, [2014106-31]; digitized VHS videotape; 00:55:14
    - Consultations, 1992 May 31 and December 6, [2014106-32]; digitized VHS videotape; 00:40:34
  - File no 28
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
  - File no. 29
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
  - File no. 30
    - Medicide folder (Box 8)
    - Consultation, 1992 March 29, [2014106-33]; digitized VHS videotape; 01:44:00
    - Consultation, 1993 May 3, [2014106-34]; digitized VHS videotape; 00:46:41
    - Consultation, 1992 May 9, [2014106-35]; digitized VHS videotape; 00:44:27
  - File no. 31
    - Consultation, 1993 March 4, digitized audio cassette
      - [Side 1 of 1], [2014106-SR-4-1]
        Content begins at 0:35.
  - Correspondence, 1995-1998, 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Medicide families (Box 8)
  - Presentation slides (Box 8)